hi spring fans in today's installment
嗨，今天的文章中的春季粉丝
we're gonna talk about distributed
我们要谈论分布式
transactions or rather distributed locks
事务或分布式锁
with spring integration now this feature
与 Spring Integration 现在这个功能
along with the leadership election was
领导选举是
actually something that came from
其实是从
another project in spring cloud and has
Spring Cloud 中的另一个项目
since been sort of put together inside
因为已经放在一起了
of spring innovation in today's
今天的春季创新
installment we're gonna very briefly
分期付款，我们将非常简短
look at distributed locks and we're
看分布式锁，我们
gonna do so of course using my second
当然要用我的第二个
favorite place on the internet start
互联网上最喜欢的地方
that spring guy oh no run one start diet
那个 Spring 的家伙，哦，没有跑一个开始饮食
yeah we are and we built the application
是的，我们已经建立了应用程序
here to that two om three we're gonna
这里是三个到三个
call this locks and we will build an
称之为锁，我们将建立一个
application here using JDBC and
使用JDBC和
PostgreSQL
PostgreSQL的
and spring integration and that's it the
和 Spring Integration ，仅此而已
other dependencies we'll just have to
其他依赖项，我们只需要
add manually there okay I guess we can
在那里手动添加好吧，我想我们可以
do distributed locks with spring
用Spring 做分布式锁
integration suppose it's better than
集成比它好
better safe than sorry and we'll open
安全胜过遗憾，我们将打开
that up
那个
and now in order to make this work we
现在为了使这项工作
need to add a few dependencies here
需要在这里添加一些依赖
we're going to bring in the spring
我们要带来 Spring
integration of JDBC support so that's a
集成了JDBC支持，因此
custom dependency and under the spring
自定义依赖关系和 Spring
integration project but thankfully it's
集成项目，但值得庆幸的是
managed for us by the spring integration
通过 Spring Integration 为我们管理
Bill of Materials so we can just import
材料清单，以便我们可以导入
it without qualification all right okay
没有资格就可以了
good stuff now let's go through our
好东西，现在让我们来看看
application and I'll rename this locks
应用程序，我将重命名此锁
or something all right good stuff okay
还是好东西好吗
there's our application now what are we
现在有我们的应用程序
gonna do well we're gonna talk to a
要做好，我们要和一个
database so let's use a we're gonna move
数据库，所以我们使用一个我们要移动的数据库
that posguys here and what we're trying
在这里，我们正在尝试什么
to do is to create a thing that will
要做的是创造一个可以
allow us to restrict access to some sort
允许我们限制某种访问
of state across multiple nodes in a
跨多个节点的状态
cluster so you might have 10 different
群集，因此您可能有10个不同的
microservices and you want to make sure
微服务，您要确保
that at any given time only one of them
在任何给定的时间里只有一个
is operating on some sort of interesting
正在某种有趣的方式上进行操作
State and that could be a resource in a
状态，这可能是一个资源
database it could be a file on a file
数据库可能是文件上的文件
system it could be it can be whatever it
系统可能是任何东西
could even be that you want to serialize
甚至可能是您要序列化
processing of requests for a particular
处理特定请求
user so you wanna make sure that while
用户，因此您想确保
somebody is updated while one node is
一个节点更新时有人更新
processing a message intended to update
处理打算更新的消息
the state of a particular user nobody
特定用户的状态没人
else in the system processes that same
其他在系统中处理相同
update basically that nobody else
基本上没有人更新
processes in the update related to that
更新中与此相关的过程
entity until one node has had a chance
实体，直到一个节点有机会
to do that so whatever the use case is
做到这一点，无论用例是什么
distributed locks are invaluable and
分布式锁非常宝贵，
ensuring inconsistency for certain kinds
确保某些种类的不一致
of use case and spring integration
用例和spring集成
provides a nice set of primitives that
提供了一组不错的原语
we can use to support that so we're
我们可以用来支持它，所以我们
gonna talk to a postcode database here
要在这里与邮政编码数据库交谈
that is available here
在这里可用
and localhost 5432 and orders okay
和本地主机5432，命令还可以
username equals orders and password
用户名等于命令和密码
equals orders all right that's my thing
等于命令好吧，这是我的事
I'm gonna do one serve it up court will
我要去法庭上发球
be equal to zero so because I'm going to
等于零，所以因为我要
start up multiple instances after all
毕竟启动多个实例
and I wanted to get I want each instance
我想让我想要每个实例
to get his own unique report and then in
得到他自己独特的报告，然后
the application we're gonna write a
我们要编写的应用程序
little bit of a positive code to save
要保存的一点积极代码
things data to the database and what I'm
东西数据到数据库，我是什么
not even nothing too fancy hairdos just
甚至没有什么太花哨的发型
do a custom repository very simple
做一个自定义的仓库很简单
repository using JDBC keep it simple
使用JDBC的存储库使其保持简单
okay I know I'm gonna need a role mapper
好吧，我知道我需要一个角色映射器
what I need an entity of type
我需要什么类型的实体
reservation
保留
so we're just using the regular Big Easy
所以我们只使用常规的Big Easy
template spinning spring forever so not
模板旋转Spring 永远不会
alive not a lot of code that we have to
活着的代码不是很多
write we can just use Lombok to bring in
写我们可以只用龙目岛带来
the right dependent retrain the you know
正确的依赖者再培训
to help us out with the boilerplate them
帮助我们解决这些难题
the constructor is the to string the
构造函数是将字符串
hash code etc that kind of stuff so
哈希码等这类东西
we'll do that here and data is
我们在这里做，数据是
constructor no it seems it constructor
构造函数，似乎没有构造函数
and there's a there's this okay and call
还有一个可以的电话
this sort of pause three good stuff okay
这样的停顿三个好东西好吗
so there's this now we want we want a
所以现在我们想要我们想要一个
couple methods here one optional of
这里有几种可选的方法
reservation okay find my ID integer ID
保留好找到我的ID整数ID
I'm gonna come back to this in a second
我一会儿再讲
and then we'll have a reservation save
然后我们将保留预订
okay come back to that in a second and
好吧，再过一秒钟再说
we'll have a collection to find all okay
我们将有一个集合来找到所有没事的
reservation fine I know I'm gonna come
预订很好，我知道我会来
back to that and second now let's do the
回到第二点，现在开始
easy one first I suppose that's this one
首先，我想很简单
so we'll say template query select all
所以我们说模板查询全选
from reservations all right I'm going to
从保留，我要去
use the row mapper and there we go
使用行映射器，然后我们去
that's the entire thing we want to do
这就是我们要做的全部事情
the same thing for fine by ID but if it
通过ID可以罚款
doesn't exist then we want to turn an
不存在，那么我们想转向
empty optional okay so what does that
空可选好吧那是什么
give us
给我们
good and we're going to provide a sequel
好，我们将提供续集
query a row mapper and the parameter the
查询行映射器和参数
parameter is the ID when I say
我说的时候参数就是ID
reservation where ID equals question
ID等于问题的保留
mark okay save it evasions let's say if
标记好了，可以避开它，如果说
reservations that size greater than zero
大小大于零的保留
then we can return optional lot of
然后我们可以返回很多
notable reservations dot in rate or dot
显着的保留率或点
next else just return optional empty
接下来的其他只是返回可选的空
okay good so that's that's the next one
好的，那就是下一个
and then finally we need to save data
最后我们需要保存数据
when asked to and so this one's very
当被问到，所以这是非常
straightforward believe it or not this
坦率的信不信由你
one is a template I'm going to execute
一个是我要执行的模板
it clearly when I say update or you know
当我说更新或您知道时，它会很清楚
yeah you wanna update when I have that
是的，当我有那个时，你想更新
okay
好的
so update reservation set name equals
因此更新预订集名称等于
question mark where I D equals question
ID等于问题的问号
mark then we have a here a prepared
标记，然后我们有一个准备
statement setter so it's a new prepared
语句设置器，这是一个新的准备
statement callback for a reservation all
全部保留的语句回调
right I'm gonna say
对，我要说
prepared statement set inch one equals
准备好的陈述将英寸等于1
two reservation got to get name all
两个保留都得到了所有的名字
right sorry I said string and then this
对不起，我说了字符串，然后这个
would be the int to sit all right and
会好好坐着，然后
then finally just find the results so
然后终于找到结果了
find by ID reservation doesn't get ID
按ID查找预订未获取ID
dot get to assume that by this point
点开始假设到这一点
with a valid record
有有效记录
okay okay so these are there's all of
好的，好的，这些都是
our code we can return the result of
我们的代码，我们可以返回的结果
course drop that out good so this is a
当然丢掉那个好，所以这是一个
repository we don't really care about
我们并不真正在乎的存储库
the repository so much we just need that
仓库太多了，我们只需要
table to write the code that uses it
表编写使用它的代码
okay so drop this and now we can say
好吧，现在放下，现在我们可以说
let's create a risk controller it allows
让我们创建一个允许的风险控制器
us to demonstrate what happens here so I
我们来证明这里发生了什么，所以我
suppose I should have brought in this
假设我应该带进去
web support for spring boot okay
Web支持Spring Boot可以
web list controller class locked oops
Web列表控制器类锁定的操作
lost resource controller okay and we'd
失去了资源控制器，我们会
have an endpoint here called update that
在这里有一个端点称为update
takes the idea of the thing we want the
想到了我们想要的东西
name want to give it and the time we
名字想给它和时间我们
want to wait afterwards so reservation
想要稍后再等，所以保留
update pack variable integer ID a
更新包变量整数ID a
credible spoon name pack animal long
可靠的勺子名字包动物长
time right so there's our endpoint and
正确的时间，所以我们有终点
when you use of course our reservation
当您使用我们的预订时
or posture right
或姿势正确
good and here we go so here's how it's
好，我们去了，所以这是怎么回事
gonna happen we want to build right we
将会发生，我们想建立正确的我们
wanna be able to update the data okay so
想能够更新数据，所以
here's the business logic the business
这是业务的业务逻辑
logic is do the following right so we're
逻辑是执行以下正确的操作，所以我们
going to say that we want to do so avoid
会说我们想避免
do a 8 or integer ID okay name and here
做一个8或整数ID好的名称，然后在这里
let's say patient we're gonna say we
假设患者我们要说我们
want to say find the repository find the
要说找到存储库，找到
record by its ID if the data is present
如果有数据，则按其ID记录
then we use the editor to set the name
然后我们使用编辑器设置名称
to that and then we save it so we say
为此，然后我们保存它，所以我们说
those are impossible to save or update
这些是不可能保存或更新的
okay
好的
and once that's done
一旦完成
we want to find the data so find my idea
我们想找到数据，所以找到我的主意
again ID don't get all right
再次ID不正确
now we've got the business object we got
现在我们有了业务对象
the reservation result equals you update
预订结果等于您更新
for ID you with name now what we want to
为您的名字ID我们现在要
protect this code Pat this this one line
保护此代码将此行拍为此行
you want to protect it so that only one
您想要保护它，以便只有一个
thing in the entire system can do that
整个系统中的事情可以做到
at a time for a particular user in this
一次针对特定用户
case the user will you know what we will
如果用户知道您将要做什么
use the ID of the user as a key so we
使用用户的ID作为密钥，因此我们
don't mind if other people execute this
不要介意别人是否执行此操作
method for other users but if if two
其他用户的方法，但如果两个
nodes are executing the same code path
节点执行相同的代码路径
for the same user then we want to you
对于同一用户，我们想要您
know make it exclusive only one thing
知道让它独占一件事
can update that user at a time okay any
可以一次更新该用户
one particular user so here we can use
一个特定的用户，所以我们可以在这里使用
the lock support okay so I'm gonna say
锁支持好吧，我要说
that we want to create a default lock
我们想要创建一个默认锁
repository okay turn new default block
存储库可以，请打开新的默认块
footpath story passing in a data source
数据源中传递的小径故事
already passing that in and then return
已经传递了，然后返回
it to JDBC lock registry and the jeebies
它到JDBC锁定注册表和jeebies
like registry it's the thing that you
就像注册表一样，这就是你的事情
can you know that's the thing that backs
你能知道那是支持的东西吗
the data that's VM implements where we
VM实施的数据
store the information about lock and
存储有关锁的信息，并
that's why we can see the same state
这就是为什么我们可以看到相同的状态
across multiple nodes because we're
跨多个节点，因为我们
talking to JDBC there are of course
与JDBC交谈当然有
other kind of locks so here's the core
其他类型的锁，这是核心
abstraction you can see this JDBC
你可以看到这个JDBC的抽象
there's a few others there's actually
还有其他一些
Venice based one if using if you spring
如果使用 Spring 的话，威尼斯就设一个
integration Venice so you know you've
融入威尼斯，让您知道自己
got options it doesn't have to be JDBC I
有选项，它不一定是JDBC I
just happen to like it and we need the
碰巧喜欢它，我们需要
lock repository that's this right here
锁定存储库就在这里
okay now we can use that here lock
好吧，现在我们可以在这里使用锁
registry
注册表
and the Leopards tree we say okay
还有豹子树，我们说好
registry dot obtained and when you use
获得的注册表点以及使用时
the key here so spring key equals
这里的钥匙，所以Spring 钥匙等于
integer to string ID okay okay good got
整数到字符串ID好好好了
the lock and then we're gonna try and
锁，然后我们将尝试
obtain the law or get a reference to it
获得法律或获得法律参考
so we'll say try and lock better just
所以我们会说尝试锁定更好
specify a timeout so I'm gonna say I
指定一个超时，所以我要说我
want to wait a second I'm willing to
想等一下我愿意
wait one whole second for that result
等待一秒钟的结果
okay now this could throw an exception
好吧，这可能会引发异常
playing these sneaky throws to tell
玩这些偷偷摸摸的掷球告诉
Lombok to swallow that potential
龙目岛吞噬了这种潜力
exception and I can say lock acquired
异常，我可以说获得锁
question mark can any closer though
问号可以关闭
until we're gonna say okay if lock
直到我们对锁说好
acquired then do that okay and actually
获得然后做那好吧，实际上
want to do this as well let's say try
也想这样做
finally so then it's lock to unlock okay
终于，所以解锁就可以了
now um we've gotten the lock we've done
现在，我们已经完成了锁定
the business logic inside with a lock
带有锁的内部业务逻辑
and then we've scheduled that when the
然后我们安排了当
work is done we unlock okay and if we
工作已经完成，我们可以解锁，如果我们
don't have a lock then you know actually
没有锁，那么你实际上知道
we can just do we can actually clean
我们可以做到，我们实际上可以清洁
this up a little bit this make this void
这一点使这无效
so there's a business there's the
所以有生意，有
skeletal pattern right to build Jesus so
建造耶稣的骨骼模式权利
we're saying do the business logic but
我们说的是业务逻辑，但是
only for inside the lock and if you're
仅用于锁内，如果
in the lock then make sure to unlock it
在锁中，然后确保将其解锁
when you're when you finish up okay good
当你完蛋的时候好
okay let's try it out so we're gonna run
好吧，让我们尝试一下，让我们开始吧
this two different times in order to run
这两个不同的时间才能运行
two times i need to get rid this we're
两次我需要摆脱这个，我们
in the program
在程序中
hello
你好
we need the ID in the the name knowing
我们需要名称中的ID知道
so RS dot get int ID and good stuff
所以RS点会得到int ID和好东西
of course lambda
当然是lambda
okay
好的
so now localhost:8080 for side 80-84
所以现在本地80:84的localhost：8080
slash and then update right so we said
斜杠然后正确更新，所以我们说
update ID and let's look at the idea we
更新ID，让我们看看我们的想法
have a sequel okay let's update
续集好吧，让我们更新
reservation set name equals in 81 and I
预订集名称等于81，而我
got Jane and John Jane is number one
得到简和约翰·简是第一
okay so we're gonna go to the default
好的，我们将使用默认值
port here right one to update one winner
在这里移植一个更新一位获胜者
gonna sleep for 30 seconds that's 30
要睡30秒就是30
seconds paper over here we're gonna
秒纸在这里，我们要
sleep for one second or 10 seconds even
甚至睡一秒钟或十秒钟
right so let's try it out here's the
对，所以让我们尝试一下
here's the 30 seconds and if so think
这是30秒，如果这样想
about what's gonna happen I'm gonna
关于将会发生什么我会
invoke the 30 second one that'll that'll
调用30秒就会
basically keep the lock open for 30
基本上把锁打开30
seconds and then very quickly in less
秒，然后在更少的时间内很快
time than 30 seconds I'm gonna go over
时间超过30秒，我要过去
there and start off the second tab and
在那里开始第二个选项卡，
that's gonna complete well before the
那将在
first one finishes because they're in a
第一个完成，因为他们在
lock the second one should never get a
锁定第二个永远不会得到一个
chance to update the state of the record
有机会更新记录的状态
in the database to match the name that
在数据库中匹配名称
we're giving him so it'll never show up
我们给他，所以它永远不会出现
as as a as new deter and keep in mind
作为新的威慑力，并牢记
we've got the update here oh we have to
我们在这里有更新哦，我们必须
do thread sleep time okay and
做线程睡眠时间还可以
I need to lunch it twice
我要吃两次午餐
okay so the first node just writing on
好吧，所以第一个节点只写
this board okay and the second node
这个板还可以，第二个节点
don't let it alone take ten seconds just
不要让它花十秒钟
load it on this note port okay so here
可以将它加载到此笔记端口上，所以在这里
we go thirty seconds ten seconds so the
我们走了三十秒十秒，所以
first one's already returned you can see
第一个已经回来，你可以看到
that it doesn't say Jane
它没有说简
it doesn't say winner loser it says Jane
它没有说失败者，而是说简
or John you can see in the background
或约翰，您可以在后台看到
there
那里
the first one is still spinning it's
第一个还在旋转
waiting 30 seconds
等待30秒
Oh
哦
what did I do wrong oh I always did it
我做错了什么哦，我总是这么做
wrong
错误
the paired statement dot execute okay
配对的语句点执行正常
take two
拿两个
all right so now this is the first note
好的，现在这是第一个音符
it's on port five one three ninety three
它在港口五一三九十三
and then this one is the second node
然后这个是第二个节点
four five one four wait so the second
四五一四等所以第二
one says
一个说
loser why did we
失败者我们为什么
okay let's try this again like that too
好吧，让我们再像这样尝试一次
here's the first one 30 seconds here's
这是第一个30秒
the second one
第二个
this is the first port it is over here
这是这里的第一个港口
on the window side and then over here on
在窗户一侧，然后在这里
the loser side there's over here okay
失败者那边在那边好
ready
准备
they go
他们去
so you can see loser never this is the
所以你可以看到失败者永远不会是
old value remember this is still the old
旧的价值，记住这仍然是旧的
value so let it finish but it's already
价值，让它完成，但它已经
updated the state you can see that
更新状态，您可以看到
because it returned when I did a query
因为它在我查询时返回
and I asked for the current state I got
我问我现在的状态
winner over here on the loser side it
在失败者这边的赢家
didn't update itself already so remember
还没有更新自己，所以请记住
it the the thing runs it writes the
它运行的东西写
state to the database and then it sleeps
状态到数据库，然后休眠
so the value here is winner if I over
所以如果我超过了，这里的价值就是赢家
here is winner which means that it never
这是赢家，这意味着它永远不会
you know it never got to the point ever
你知道它永远都没有意义
let loser enter or execute okay so there
让失败者进入或执行，所以在那里
you go there's a very simple distributed
你去那里有一个非常简单的分布式
locks algorithm kind of you know
锁算法，你知道吗
situation or example kind of cool I
情况或例子酷我
haven't had a chance to really play with
没有机会真正玩
this stuff before but you know I can I
这些东西以前，但你知道我可以
can see a lot of different use cases
可以看到很多不同的用例
obviously this is really great if you
显然，如果您
have like message resequencing or that
像消息重新排序或
kind of stuff if you want to make sure
如果您想确保某种东西
that you have only one person updating a
您只有一个人更新
particular egg at a time if you have
如果您有一个鸡蛋，一次一次
some sort of stateful thing like a file
某种有状态的东西，例如文件
in a file system or you know some sort
在文件系统中，或者您知道某种
of session that you want to control
您要控制的会话
whatever right you can actually do some
不管你实际上可以做些什么
very interesting things here with these
这些非常有趣的事情
distributed locks I'm using the JDBC
我正在使用JDBC的分布式锁
based one because I suspect that a lot
基于一个，因为我怀疑很多
of people have that infrastructure
有基础设施
available on the machines or in their
在机器上或在他们的机器上可用
services but you can use those things
服务，但您可以使用这些东西
there's a Redis spaced one and I think
有一个Redis隔开的，我认为
the reddest one is probably gonna be
最红的可能是
faster I don't know about it but I I
更快，我不知道，但是
expect that you know given what we know
期望您知道我们所知道的
about Redis and how fast it is and how
关于Redis，它有多快以及如何
tuned it is for this this particular use
调整此特定用途
case I'll bet it's probably very fast if
情况下，我敢打赌，如果
you sure when they give that a shot so
你确定他们什么时候拍的
my friends I hope you enjoyed this as
我的朋友们，我希望你喜欢
always and we'll see you next time
总是，我们下次见
you
您